<jordan1>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Fearless UNC Chicago</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2019-02-11</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>White/University Blue-Varsity Red-Black</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">160.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">440.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>CK5666-100</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/uncchicago.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>Following the same winning formulate as 2018’s Union LA collaboration, the Jordan 1 Fearless takes colour blocking to the next level, with the iconic ‘UNC’ arriving on the ankle and heel and the legendary ‘Chicago‘ making its way to the midfoot and toebox. Finished in a glossy patent leather for a shimmering vibe, black accents also feature on the Swoosh and laces for a further pop of contrast. Along the insole, Michael Jordan’s famous basketball Hall of Fame induction speech is printed, “Limits, like fear, are often just an illusion.” with the word “FEAR” crossed out for dramatic effect. What’s better than the ‘UNC’ or the ‘Chicago’? The Jordan 1 Fearless of course! Scheduled to hit shelves sometime in 2019, you need to go true to size for the best fit possible!</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/uncchicago2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro Fragment</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2014-12-27</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Black/Sport Blue-White</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">185.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">4885.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>716371-040</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/fragment.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>This upgraded version of the original Jumpman silhouette stays faithful to the OG design. The pair is dressed in a blue, white and blue mixed colourway. The shoe also includes the hallmark nine loop design and perforated toe-box. The uppers are upgraded with premium leather construction with the iconic Wings decal to the ankle. There is also the tonal Fragment Design marque to the heel panel.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/fragment2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Travis Scott</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2019-05-11</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Sail/Black-Dark Mocha-University Red</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">175.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">1761.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>CD4487-100</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/travisscott.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>Since the beginning of time, the Jordan 1 has always been one of Jumpman’s most iconic silhouettes, and the Travis Scott x Jordan 1 Backwards Swoosh Mocha perfectly embodies everything that makes the sneaker so legendary. Understated yet unique, this shoe features a familiar yet different aesthetic compared to other Jordan 1 silhouettes, and it takes some of Jordan Brand’s classic features and combines them with a clean and contemporary design. Leaked in October, the Travis Scott x Jordan 1 Backwards Swoosh is painted in a ‘Dark Mocha’ and ‘Black’ colour scheme. Crafted from a slew of premium materials, the collaborative shoe is marked by a blend of brown, earthy tones which is perfect for the autumn months. A flipped Swoosh adorns the lateral midfoot side, while a Cactus Jack motif is present on the tongue. A feature that you may not know is the pocket that is hidden around the ankle region to hold your secret stash.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/travis2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Dark Mocha</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2020-10-31</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Sail/Dark Mocha-Black</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">170.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">528.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-105</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/darkmocha.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>The Jordan 1 Dark Mocha is the latest high-heat colourway of the highly-coveted Air Jordan 1 silhouette that’s gearing up for release from Jordan Brand. The AJ1 was Michael Jordan’s first ever signature sneaker and originally released in high, mid and low-top variations. It remains one of the most popular sneakers of all time and releases are always ultra-hyped. We've got official images and a detailed look at the wannabe Cactus Jack pair right here, so read on for more! Seen here in a clean Dark Mocha colourway that’s heavily reminiscent of Travis Scott's highly in-demand collaboration, the Air Jordan 1 looks better than ever crafted from genuine nubuck leather and premium brushed suede. Nike’s iconic Swoosh logo runs neatly down each side, while Nike Air branding and the Wings logo remain at the tongue and collar respectively. The brown and black tones are neatly balanced with white panels for a well-considered colourway. The toe box is perforated in classic Michael Jordan fashion, while black leather accents give off a black toe vibe for a classic look.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/darkmocha2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Court Purple White</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2020-04-11</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Court Purple/White-Black</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">170.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">359.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-500</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/courtpurple.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>When it comes to new AJ1 colourways, the Jordan 1 Court Purple 2020 is up there as one of the most hyped releases of the year. First leaked back in December, this shoe bears a striking resemblance to the Dunk High "Co.JP" which made its debut over twenty years ago in 1999, and we think it's a definite must cop. Receiving the classic colour blocked treatment that has graced Jordan Brand's signature line since the early '80s, the Court Purple is decked out in purple and white panels with black detailing hitting the lateral and medial Swoosh and flat laces. Crafted from premium tumbled leather that's soft and smooth to the touch, the sheer quality really has to be seen to be believed. Down below, Nike's famed Air technology makes its way to the midsoles for an insane amount of comfort with every step, and this is lined with a complementary rubber outsole that ties it all up nicely. Rounding it all off is the iconic winged basketball motif that's finely embossed onto the heel in black, finalising the design.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/purple2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Shadow 2.0</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2021-05-15</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Black/White-Light Smoke Grey</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">170.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">252.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-035</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/highshadow.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>If you are a dedicated Jordan 1 collector, then you should take a closer look at the high-heat Jordan 1 High OG Shadow 2.0. At first look, it appears that this pair holds the same colour arrangement as the OG Shadow colourway. However, additional images display a colour blocking scheme slightly different from the original release, therefore, we have no doubts that these are an absolute banger to sneakerheads and Jordan fans alike. Arriving in a high-top silhouette that's popular as ever, the upper works on a black leather base while light grey suede overlays run from the toe box to the heel. Across the side panels, the shoe proudly displays Nike's iconic Swoosh logo completed with Michael Jordan's wings emblem on the lateral ankle collar and Jumpman branding on the tongue. Beneath the feet, a full-length crisp white midsole unit is present as ever concealed with Nike Air technology to give all your strides, turns and jumps on the court an insane amount of cushioning and comfort. Finally, a black rubber outsole underfoot that provides better traction on any surface ensures that these AJ1 are slip-resistant.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/shadow2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High OG Hyper Royal</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2021-04-17</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Hyper Royal/Light Smoke Grey-White</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">170.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">360.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-402</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/hyperroyal.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>The Jordan 1 Retro High OG Hyper Royal is the latest AJ1 OG colourway that has many sneakerheads globally dying to get their hands on. The Air Jordan 1 first released in 1985 in high, low and mid-top renditions as Michael Jordan’s first-ever signature basketball shoe. It was designed by Peter Moore and has since remained one of the most popular sneakers of all time. Dressed in premium leather throughout, the uppers of the shoes take on hyper blue and grey hues, reminiscent of the classic Royal AJ1 colourway that released all the way back in 1985. Nike’s signature Swoosh logo is featured alongside a wings logo at the collar and Nike Air embroidery at the tongue. Beneath the feet, a whited-out rubber midsole unit stays true to the original design and encases Nike Air technology to ensure that these are just as comfortable off the court as they are on.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/hyperroyal2.jpeg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High White University Blue Black</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2021-03-06</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>White/University Blue-Black</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">170.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">480.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-134</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/universityblue.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>The Jordan 1 High OG University Blue is the latest in a stream of blue Air Jordan colorways to have recently been unveiled, and it looks set to be a future classic. The AJ1 was first unveiled way back in 1985 as Michael Jordan’s first-ever signature shoe and has since become one of the best-selling sneakers ever. The Jordan 1 High OG University Blue raffles list is now live on our page so don't forget to take a closer look if you are eager on adding these to your collection! Crafted from premium tumbled leather, the uppers of this Jordan 1 University Blue showcase the model’s signature colour blocking, with UNC Blue, white and black panels compiling a retro look. Nike’s iconic Swoosh logo resides on each side, while Nike Air branding is present at the tongue and a wings logo at the collar. Other classic details such as the perforated toe box are as present as ever. Underfoot, a whited-out rubber sole unit houses the uppers neatly and conceals Nike Air technology to ensure that these vintage basketball sneakers are comfortable as ever even in this day and age! Fans of Nike and Jordan Brand are already getting excited over this release, and it’s easy to see why!</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/university2.jpeg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Royal Toe</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2020-09-05</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Black/White-Game Royal-Black</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">170.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">380.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-041</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/royaltoe.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>This brand-new colourway puts a spin on the OG Royal colourway by adding in white panels for a familiar feel. The uppers are crafted entirely from premium quality leather and showcase Nike Swoosh’s on either side and additional branding such as the label’s signature wings logo and Nike Air branding at the tongue. The panelled design also showcases ample padding around the ankle and a perforated toe box. Underfoot, a clean white midsole is present that conceals Nike’s highly-coveted Air technology to ensure that they’re comfortable as ever. A blue midsole finishes the colorway neatly.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/royaltoe2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High J Balvin</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2020-08-12</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Multi-Color/Black-Pink Foam-Multi-Color</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">190.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">513.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>DC3481-900</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/jbalvin.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>The uppers are crafted from what looks to be canvas panels, with the iridescent rainbow look running from top to bottom. Cut-out frayed edges adorn the shoes too for a never-before-seen retro-inspired look, while J Balvin’s signature smiley logo at the tongue accompanies the iconic Nike Swoosh logo embellished onto the side in black. Other branding includes embroidered Jumpman logos and another smiley patch located at the rear of the shoes. Underfoot, a classic whited-out rubber midsole is present as ever, concealing the timeless Nike Air technology that hasn’t changed since the model was first introduced in 1985. Whether you’re spending time on the court or wandering the streets, we’ve got no doubts that these will keep you comfy.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/jbalvin2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro Shattered Backboard</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2015-06-27</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Black/Starfish-Sail</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">160.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">1942.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-005</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/shatteredbackboard1.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>Who doesn’t love an OG colourway on the Air Jordan range? It’s not that the contemporary releases don’t create their own hype, but there’s something about the iconic silhouettes. They take us right back to the old school where the sneaker game was simple. Forget your Primeknit’s, Flyknit’s, mesh crafted uppers and cored out midsole’s; this was a time of rugged durability through premium crafted leather. The Jordan 1 Reverse Shattered Backboard brings that heritage alive. Of course, ‘Shattered Backboard’ is a basketball term referring to those angry dunks which result in smashing the glass of the backboard. The unusual name of the shoe matches the unique colour combination utilised on the upper. A dark shade of orange, almost mustard, manages to dominate throughout. It’s complimented by white leather overlays and a large black Swoosh to the sidewall. Darker accents also make an appearance to the rear and a set of black laces are included. To complete the look, original MJ branding features to the sidewall. It’s another icon returned from the archives and we’re hyped for the release.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/shattered1.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro Reverse Shattered Backboard</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2016-08-10</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Sail/Starfish-Black</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">160.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">1337.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-113</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/shatteredbackboard2.jpeg</imgpath>
        <tekst>The colourway of the pair references the moment and the colours of the jersey Michael Jordan was wearing while playing in that game. The shoe is crafted with a premium leather and has hints of black, white and orange all throughout. It also includes an eye-catching graphic insole that references Jordans Airness; a glass-shattering backboard. There are brandings on the heel and tongue. It sits on top of a white midsole and is finished off with an orange outsole unit.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/sbb2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Shattered Backboard 3.0</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2019-10-26</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Black/Pale Vanilla-Starfish</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">160.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">407.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-028</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/shatteredbackboard3.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>The third iteration of the iconic Shattered Backboard colourway, it gets its name from an incident that occurred during Michael Jordan’s second NBA season, where he so forcefully dunked at the net that it completely shattered the glass on the backboard, and the rest is history!
        One of the most iconic sneakers since it debuted in 1985, the Shattered Backboard 3.0 is painted in a colour blocked orange and black palette, and is constructed of a combination of tumbled and patent leathers for a subtle yet striking textual contrast.
        A clean ‘Sail’ midsole gives the shoe a vintage aesthetic, and the design is finished off with the traditional perforated toe box, black laces, Swoosh branding, and the embossed winged basketball logo that’s become synonymous with Jumpman sneakers.
        A must cop for any sneaker collection, if you are searching for the perfect pair of kicks to rock both on the street and on the court, then look no further than the Jordan 1 Shattered Backboard 3.0! For the perfect fit, we recommend that you go true to size!</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/shattered3.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro UNC</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2015-10-10</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>White/Dark Powder Blue</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">160.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">953.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>555088-117</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/ogunc.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>Ultra soft and premium leather covers the upper of this Nike Air Jordan. Unlike some of the newer Jumpman styles, this pair stays entirely true to the old school. In fact, the look and feel is almost identical to those classic 80s high-tops.
        Michael Jordan’s first ever basketball crep looks especially eye-catching in  combination of cream, navy and vibrant blue. Otherwise known as the AJ1 ‘Obsidian University Blue’ this pair brings just the right amount of colour to your summer wardrobe.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/unc2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Off-White White</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2018-03-03</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>White/White</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">190.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">3976.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>AQ0818-100</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/offwhitewhite.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>Virgil Abloh is fast becoming one of the major names in sneaker design. Just like his close friend Kanye West, this visionary is pushing the boundaries and setting trends. The ‘White’ Off-White x Jordan 1 is all together more simple than the OG colourway. That said, all the same details make an appearance.
        Once again, Virgil opts for a deconstructed theme. Premium leather overlays sit across a mesh crafted upper. The Swoosh is sewn-on across the sidewall whilst a chunky and soft tongue keeps the foot securely locked in place.
        The Off-White x Jordan 1 White is stamped with signature markings which makes this range so appealing. That includes the “AIR” insignia along the midsole as well as the vibrant hits of orange. Unlike the OG design, this pair features a baby blue coloured cable-tie.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/ow.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Off-White Chicago</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2017-09-09</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>White/Black-Varsity Red</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">190.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">5934.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>AA3834-101</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/offwhitechicago.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>Virgil Abloh is fast becoming one of the major names in sneaker design. Just like his close friend Kanye West, this visionary is pushing the boundaries and setting trends. The ‘White’ Off-White x Jordan 1 is all together more simple than the OG colourway. That said, all the same details make an appearance.
        Once again, Virgil opts for a deconstructed theme. Premium leather overlays sit across a mesh crafted upper. The Swoosh is sewn-on across the sidewall whilst a chunky and soft tongue keeps the foot securely locked in place.
        The Off-White x Jordan 1 White is stamped with signature markings which makes this range so appealing. That includes the “AIR” insignia along the midsole as well as the vibrant hits of orange. Unlike the OG design, this pair features a baby blue coloured cable-tie.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/ow.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Off-White University Blue</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2018-06-23</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>White/Dark Powder Blue-Cone</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">190.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">2247.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>AQ0818-148</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/offwhiteunc.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>Virgil Abloh is fast becoming one of the major names in sneaker design. Just like his close friend Kanye West, this visionary is pushing the boundaries and setting trends. The ‘White’ Off-White x Jordan 1 is all together more simple than the OG colourway. That said, all the same details make an appearance.
        Once again, Virgil opts for a deconstructed theme. Premium leather overlays sit across a mesh crafted upper. The Swoosh is sewn-on across the sidewall whilst a chunky and soft tongue keeps the foot securely locked in place.
        The Off-White x Jordan 1 White is stamped with signature markings which makes this range so appealing. That includes the “AIR” insignia along the midsole as well as the vibrant hits of orange. Unlike the OG design, this pair features a baby blue coloured cable-tie.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/ow.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 Retro High Trophy Room Chicago</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>2021-10-02</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>White/Varsity Red-Sail-Black</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">190.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">3037.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>DA2728-100</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/trophyroom.jpg</imgpath>
        <tekst>In collaboration with Marcus Jordan's Trophy Room, this forthcoming AJ1 holds a value that is highly sentimental to a lot of Jordan heads as the Trophy Room is a boutique owned by the son of Michael Jordan and can only be found inside his mansion in Chicago. But above all, this pair pays respects to NBA's legendary "freeze-out" which took place during the 1985 All-Star Game.
        Arriving in a colour palette of the OG Chicago colourway that we all know and love, the Trophy Room Air Jordan 1 works on a white leather upper accentuated with glittery red overlays for a luxurious sneaker aesthetic. Michael Jordan's autograph makes an appearance on the lateral heel while the Wings logo can be seen embossed on the ankle collar for a signature touch.
        Down below, Nike's Air technology makes its way to a crisp white midsole lined with a translucent outsole for an insane amount of comfort both on and off the court, finalising this special edition kicks.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/trophy2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 OG Chicago (1985)</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>1985-09-16</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>White/Black-Red</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">65.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">35000.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>4280</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/ogchicago.jpeg</imgpath>
        <tekst>The Nike “Air Jordan” is one of the most iconic designs in the history of both streetwear and basketball, and is a key part of the origin of the Air Jordan brand for Nike. Designed by Peter Moore, Michael Jordan wore Air Jordan 1s in 1984 and 1985, as well as modified versions in 1986 (after a broken foot Michael endured).
        In 1984, Nike gave Michael Jordan his own signature line of shoes and clothes, which was pivotal in Michael agreeing to sign with Nike. It was the first time the brand did anything like this, and it paved the way for many of the player collaborations we now see. The term “Air Jordan” was coined by Michael Jordan’s agent David Falk. David apparently came up with the name because Nike shoes had air in the soles and because, of course, Michael Jordan played basketball in the air.
        In terms of the shoe itself, the original Air Jordan 1s were so popular and successful that Nike continued to make new signature Air Jordans each season. This tradition continued beyond Michael’s retirement, and Nike is currently on the Air Jordan 35. From the day it launched, Air Jordans have always represented the pinnacle of sneaker design. The shoes are unmatched when it comes to quality, craftsmanship, materials, innovation, performance, and of course style.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/og1.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 OG Bred (1985)</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>1985-09-15</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Black/Varsity Red-White</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">65.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">35000.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>4285</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/ogbred.jpeg</imgpath>
        <tekst>The Nike “Air Jordan” is one of the most iconic designs in the history of both streetwear and basketball, and is a key part of the origin of the Air Jordan brand for Nike. Designed by Peter Moore, Michael Jordan wore Air Jordan 1s in 1984 and 1985, as well as modified versions in 1986 (after a broken foot Michael endured).
        In 1984, Nike gave Michael Jordan his own signature line of shoes and clothes, which was pivotal in Michael agreeing to sign with Nike. It was the first time the brand did anything like this, and it paved the way for many of the player collaborations we now see. The term “Air Jordan” was coined by Michael Jordan’s agent David Falk. David apparently came up with the name because Nike shoes had air in the soles and because, of course, Michael Jordan played basketball in the air.
        In terms of the shoe itself, the original Air Jordan 1s were so popular and successful that Nike continued to make new signature Air Jordans each season. This tradition continued beyond Michael’s retirement, and Nike is currently on the Air Jordan 35. From the day it launched, Air Jordans have always represented the pinnacle of sneaker design. The shoes are unmatched when it comes to quality, craftsmanship, materials, innovation, performance, and of course style.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/bred1.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
    <model>
        <naziv>Jordan 1 OG Royal (1985)</naziv>
        <datumIzlaska>1985-09-15</datumIzlaska>
        <boja>Black/Royal Blue</boja>
        <maloprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">65.00</maloprodajnaCijena>
        <preprodajnaCijena valuta="USD">40040.00</preprodajnaCijena>
        <styleCode>4282</styleCode>
        <imgpath>images/ogroyal.jpeg</imgpath>
        <tekst>The Nike “Air Jordan” is one of the most iconic designs in the history of both streetwear and basketball, and is a key part of the origin of the Air Jordan brand for Nike. Designed by Peter Moore, Michael Jordan wore Air Jordan 1s in 1984 and 1985, as well as modified versions in 1986 (after a broken foot Michael endured).
        In 1984, Nike gave Michael Jordan his own signature line of shoes and clothes, which was pivotal in Michael agreeing to sign with Nike. It was the first time the brand did anything like this, and it paved the way for many of the player collaborations we now see. The term “Air Jordan” was coined by Michael Jordan’s agent David Falk. David apparently came up with the name because Nike shoes had air in the soles and because, of course, Michael Jordan played basketball in the air.
        In terms of the shoe itself, the original Air Jordan 1s were so popular and successful that Nike continued to make new signature Air Jordans each season. This tradition continued beyond Michael’s retirement, and Nike is currently on the Air Jordan 35. From the day it launched, Air Jordans have always represented the pinnacle of sneaker design. The shoes are unmatched when it comes to quality, craftsmanship, materials, innovation, performance, and of course style.</tekst>
        <imgpath2>images/ogroyal2.jpg</imgpath2>
    </model>
</jordan1>